So now we can use
the input to rotate the
bolt, we're going to translate
this to creating some movement.
We'll go back into our player
controller script here and you
can see that we'll start
adjusting this to make it happen.
The rotation speed that we had,
we can rename this to a player
speed just to make this more
suitable for what we're going to use.
We're going to also want a reference to
our rigid body that's on our player to make
it show that we can cause it to
have some forces to make it move.
Underneath that input system variable, we'll
have another private variable, it's going
to be type rigid body
and we're going to give
this a name of player
RB with a semicolon.
So then we can use this.
We also do need to make sure that we find
it in a wake to cache the reference because
it's great to just do this once
before everything initializes.
So we'll say player RB
equals get component
and then in the angle
brackets left and right
we'll have rigid body,
the parentheses and
the semicolon because we're just
finding that component that we need.
Now in the side, the update
method where we had the move
input, the forward input
and the transform dot rotate.
In this case, we don't want
transform dot rotate anymore.
We can just rename this and we can use
something different so we'll say player RB is
what we can use and we'll say
dot add force because we want to
force the right to body with
some elements of force in that.
So to move it forward,
we'll use another vector
three, but instead of
up, we'll use a vector
three dot forward because we want to push
it in that direction and instead of having
a comma here, we're going to times that
by the forward input that we already had.
Then we multiply the
rotation speed, but we
also need to get the
player speed and replace
that so it's multiplied the player
speed, multiplied by time dot delta time.
Then we can save this out.
Now our player has the
rigid body and the play
controller with the player
speed of around 150.
If we test this out, we
can move S to move
backwards and then
double you to move forwards.
It is a little bit
unresponsive so I like to
put the player speed up to around 1000 and
then we get a more of a responsive take on
the movement forward
and backward and you can
up the mass and adjust
any of the drag settings
if you want this to feel slightly different
when you're controlling your character.
So what I want you to
do is go to your player
controller script and
rename the public float,
which was rotation speed
to player speed, make
sure you add a private variable
rigid body and call this player happy.
In the awake method, make sure player
happy is equal to the get components.
We need to initialize
and find the component.
Then down in the update method, we make
sure that we're using then player rigid body
dot add force and it's
going to be vector 3
dot forward times by
the forward input times
by player speed and
times by time dot delta time.
And then you can come back into unity at
just any of your rigid body settings and you
play controller player
speed and test it out.